Guide to the Roger Morse papers, 1910-2000
Morse, Roger papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Roger Morse papers, 1910-2000
21-23-4122
Roger A. Morse
3 cubic feet.
Correspondence, course material, and photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes material related to beekeeping, his membership in the Empire State Honey Producers' Association, and Morse's career in the Dept. of Entomology.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Morse was a bee biologist in the Dept. of Entomology. He received his B.A. in 1950, his master's degree in 1953, and his PhD in 1955, all from Cornell.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, course material and photographs related to beekeeping, his membership in the Empire State Honey Producers' Association, and Morse's career in the Dept. of Entomology. Also included is a bound volume titled "Burma and Nepal programs and reports," consisting of typewritten documents and correspondence concerning projects that Morse was involved with there. Its spine title is Morse--Asian journey--1982.)
SUBJECTS
Names:
Morse, Roger A.; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Cornell University. Dept. of Entomology.; Empire State Honey Producers' Association.; Cornell University; New York State College of Agriculture. Department of Entomology
Subjects:
Bees; Bee culture; Bee culture; Bees; Universities and colleges -- Faculty
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Photographs
Series II. Teaching
Series III. Empire State Honey Producers Association
CONTAINER LIST
- Photographs
  - Brazil - Dave's talk, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brazil, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bufo, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brood patterns, 1983- (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Brood patterns, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bumblebee, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Burma, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bus trip, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cage by Papadopoulo, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Paul Cappy, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dewy Caron, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Carpenter ants, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cell Orientation, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Coggshall frame nest in tree, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Combs and foundation, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Comb honey - poor combs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Comb honey - supering, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Comb equipment - swarm in tree with wax moth damage, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Comb honey, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Comb honey judging cards, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Comb honey - cobana, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Comb, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Comb honey, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Comb construction, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Comb, 1976-12 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Conner - Bee, wasp, round dance, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Contamination papers with Lisk, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Covers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Crooked comb, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Curtis trucks - Queen cells, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Crown caps and propolis on legs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Davidson's label, Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Demuth - migratory beekeeping, Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - DEW - bees wet with dew, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Doolittle's picture, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Diesease book duplicates, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Dominican Republic, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Dorsata, Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Drone fall death rates, Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Dyce Laboratory - including maps and brochure, 1969-1990 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Effect of light on comb construction, including negatives, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Effect of light on comb construction, including negatives, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Effect of light on comb construction, including negatives and memos, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Egypt, Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Bee escapes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Equipment dimensions, including negatives, Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - ETO chamber, Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Encyclopedia, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Examining hives, Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Excluders and negatives, Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Feeding bees, Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Feeding bees underneath, Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Florida, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Follower Boards, Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Foulbrood, Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Von Frisch reproduction of dances, Undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Gamber, Undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Garden book, Undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Garden, Undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Garden wood preservatives, Undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - German Bee Institute (Ruttner), Undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Carol Hansen, Undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Carol Hansen, comb honey, wax on glass, Undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Hive showing all its parts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Hive ventilation, Undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Jars of honey, Undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Roger Morse, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Exploded beehive, Undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Roger Morse, including negatives, Undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Morse and moving bees, Undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Moving bees, Undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Mrax cut comb, Undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Natural comb and queen cells, Undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Natural nest in open - comb construction, Undated (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Nepal figure, Undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - New York State pesticide loss survey, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Ohio State conference, 1987-03-1987-04 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Old photos, including National Bee-Keepers Association, Undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Woodcut, Undated (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - One year book, Undated (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Onion flowers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Dyce Lab Ontario trip, Undated (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Oswego, Undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Packages and drumming, Undated (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Package bee bulletin, 1971-02 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Magnetic field effects, Elmira 345 experiment, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Mead - photos for book, Undated (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Harold Merrell, Undated (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Honey plants, Undated (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Honey - price, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Honey pump, Undated (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Honey stand, Undated (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Bot Fly eggs, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Richard Hoy - glass hives - copy of image, 1788 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Isopentylacetate paper with Boch and Shearer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Lederhouse on flies at Archbolds - graph, 1740-2000 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Megachilie rotunda, Undated (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Package bee bulletin - duplicates and unused, 1970-06 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Packages, Undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Honey bee pests, predators, and diseases - used in book, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Variety of photos, Undated (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Sex attractant and swollen arm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Seeley - CO2 and nest size - negatives and originals, Undated (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Seeley - natural nest, Undated (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Sex attractant and drone brood, Undated (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Sex attractant, feeding bees, and brood patterns, Undated (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Sex attractant, Undated (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Sex attractant, Undated (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Sex attractant, Undated (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Skep negatives, Undated (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Skunks, Undated (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Stomachs of Philippine birds, Undated (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Swarm clusters, Undated (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Swarm data, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Swarm orientation, Undated (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Swarm orientation, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Swarm orientation, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Swarm orientation - Florida, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Swarm orientation, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Swarm orientation and megachilid nest, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Swarm orientation, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Swarm orienation and airplane spraying, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Swarm orientation, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Swarm orientation, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Swarm in rain, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Swarm in rain and benzaldehyde, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Swarm orientation, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Swarm orientation, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Swarm looking for cells, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Swarm orientation bumblebee nest, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Tests of effective pesticides on honey bees - Finger Lakes Producers Coop, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Thixotropic honey - heather plant, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Thailand, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Truck - Curtis, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Uncappers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Uniting colonies; wasp nests, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Varroa life cycle, 1991-06 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Varroa map and mites, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Varroa - Cromroy's pictures, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Varroa life cycle - Byron Alexander illustration, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Venom collection, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Venom collection, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Venom collection - small vespa nests and swarm orientation, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Venom collection and effect of light on comb construction, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Venom collection - apis indica, Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Venom collection and Xylocopa, Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Vespa ground nest, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Vespa nest on the window, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Wasp bee sting, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Watson thesis - negatives, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Wax scales and anatomy, Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Karl Weiss photo, Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - White faced hornet, Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Winter cluster, Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Wild bees, Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Wild bee nests, Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Wine photos, Undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Wintering and Dyce Lab, Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Some photo used in August 1976 bulletin
  - Winter cluster, Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Winter snow in entrance, Undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Wintering, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Wintering bulletin, Undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Winter cluster, Undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Worker attraction to synthetic baits, Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Acarapis Woodi life cycle, Undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - African hives, Undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - African bee painting - negatives, Undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Apis Cerana, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Apis Dorsata and Apis Indica, Undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Apis Dorsata, Undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Apis Dorsata in Thailand, Undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Apple trees in 1875 map, Undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Apple blossoms frost damage, Undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Appledore artificial swarm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Asian trip, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Apple polination, Undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Black label, Undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Bait hives, Undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Basswood in flower, Undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Bear bill assembly version, Undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Bee beards, Undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Beekeeping areas in New York State, Undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Beekeeper in England - Commerical, Undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Beekeeper in the Philippines, Undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Beehives, Undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Bee sting and swarm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Bee stings - Gunnison's photos, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Bee hive photos for Florida paper, Undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Bee hive photos for general information bulletin, Undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Beeswax, Undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Beeswax, Undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Beeswax, Undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Bee tree, Undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Bear photos - Helgesen, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Beeswax, Undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Old bottle negatives, Undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Poland, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Polish photos, Undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Polish hives, 1971-12-08 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Pollination, Undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Price of honey graph, Fall (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Propolis on bottom board, moving screen and natural comb contruction, Undated (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Pure Food and Drug Act of 1878, Undated (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Queen Cells, Undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Queen coge, Undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Queen cells, Undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Queen rearing and moving bees, Undated (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Queen book, Undated (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Queen cage, Undated (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Queen rearing - extension bulletin, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Scenting bee, Undated (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Sawdust collecting bees, Undated (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - E.F. Phillips, Jay Smith, J.E. Wing, George Rea, D. L. Van Dine, C.C. Miller, E.G. Carr, A.W. Yates, H.W. Coley, Bruce Lineburg and short course in Ithaca attendees, 1910-1919 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    Bureau of Entomology
  - Kenyon top bar hive, 1982-05 (Box 2, Folder 99)
- Teaching
  - Entomology 260 - elementary beekeeping course material, 1976-2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Lecture handouts, 1991-2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Entomology 260 exams, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Entomology 264 labs, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Home Study Beekeeping Courses, 1989-1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Patent application for making honey wine, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Camazine, Scott - graduate student, 1988-1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ferracane, Michael - graduate student, 1984-1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - MacKenzie, Kenna - graduate student, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Pratt, Stephen, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Gene Robinson - graduate student, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Gene Robinson - graduate student, 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Thomas Seeley, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Adrian Siceanu - visiting fellow, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Joan Spielholz - graduate student, 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Maurice Tauber - Chair Dept. of Entomology, 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Kirk Visscher - graduate student, 1978-1989 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Morse Publications, 1964, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Empire State Honey Producers Association
  - Correspondence, memos, programs, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, memos, programs, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, memos, programs, 1925-1998 (Box 3, Folder 21)